# GustavoPenha

guzpenha10@gmail.com

## about

28 years Delft, NL

#### links

webpage twitter github google scholar

## programming

Python, C++, Spark, R

#### languages

portuguese english

#### soft skills

time management communication learn and adapt

## research

I am a researcher in the fields of Information Retrieval, Recommender Systems, Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing. My PhD is focused on ranking models for conversational search & recommendation. I like to do research driven by curiosity, and one of my strengths is time management.

# selected publications

2022	Evaluating the Robustness of Retrieval Pipelines with Query Variation Generators  ECIR  Gustavo Penha, Arthur Câmara, Claudia Hauff
2021	On the Calibration and Uncertainty of Neural Learning to Rank Models for Conversational Search  EACL  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	What does BERT know about books, movies and music? Probing BERT for Conversational Recommendation RecSys Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	Curriculum Learning Strategies for IR: An Empirical Study on Conversation Response Ranking  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff  ECIR

# **experience**

2022-6–8	<b>Research Intern</b> Spotify - NL Summer internship planned.
2021-5–8	<b>Applied Research Intern</b> Amazon - US  Voice search explanations for Alexa, resulted in 2 papers (CHI'22 & CHIIR'22).
2015–2018	Data Scientist  Machine learning and data science projects. Tech lead of 1M+ R\$ project.
2014–2015	<b>Undergraduate Researcher</b> UFMG - Brazil Research on scientific collaboration networks. Coauthor in 2 papers.

# education

2019-now	Ph.D. TU Delft - Netherlan	ds
	Computer Science. 10 papers, 100+ citations and 150+ github stars.	
2012-2018	B.Sc. and M.Sc. UFMG - Bra	zil
	Computer Science. MSc work won best paper RU award at RecSys'20.	